BRIAN CLERKIN

103 Harvard Road, Fair Haven, NJ 07704 m: 973.703.7911 / brianclerkin732@gmail.com

Objective: To obtain a sales position with a leader in enterprise sales.

Summary: Award-winning sales, account management, and business development leader with 10+ year career in

healthcare IT and healthcare learning. Consistently exceeding targeted sales

and renewal goals, increasing sales revenues, and expanded pipeline at regional, national, and

international levels.

Aptitudes: Account management/ relations Pipeline growth

Business development Lead generation

Healthcare technology Company representation

Presentation skills - live, virtual Product/ solution upselling

Cross-department collaboration Subject matter expert collaboration (SME)

Budget planning Negotiations

Technology:

Current CPHIMS certificate MS in Health Admin & Healthcare Informatics

Salesforce.com, ACT!, Zoho Microsoft Office

Career:

Business Development Manager

2018- Sep, 2019

CE Direct, powered by Relias LLC, Morrisville, NC

- Hired to develop new business for this healthcare learning solutions vendor.
- Closed new sales at CVS, MetLife, University of Vermont within first five months. Responsible for renewals in a territory averaging \$750k, now on track to generate in the range of \$985k.
- Tracked all sales activity in various versions of Salesforce, generated regular activity reports complied with all sales activity reporting.

Direct Sales Manager 2015-2018

NexAge Technologies (business entity of 8K Miles), East Brunswick, NJ

- Hired to launch emerging direct sales division for IT compliance and SaaS/cloud systems integration solutions provider for pharmaceutical industry
- Immediately achieved substantial sales growth, leading to hire of 6 new account managers
- Exceeded sales quota by 32% first year with company and achieved 100% renewals through 2017 due to gaining product knowledge, SME relationship building, unique sales strategies, and upselling
- Successfully managed sizable accounts at pharmaceutical industry leaders, such as Novartis, Shire, Par Pharma, Endo, and G&W

Business Development Manager/National Manager of Healthcare Compliance Sales Guidemark Health (formark Trigoro Inc.) Princeton N.I.

2013-2015

Guidemark Health (formerly Tricore, Inc.), Princeton, NJ

- Created and executed territory business plan and oversaw sales of training services to managers and directors of pharmaceutical leaders in competitive Northeast territory, including Biogen Idec, Johnson & Johnson, and Actavis
- Established and maintained thorough knowledge of training services products and presented live, online, and virtual sales presentations to existing and potential clients to maximize new sales and cross-sell opportunities for training and education in operations, sales, compliance, market access, disease state, and finance.
- Achieved 100% of new business development goal. Grew emergent territory from \$0 to \$1.2 million within first year of hire, accounting for 13% of total company revenue
- Earned 100% second-year renewal rate
- Developed and implemented unique marketing and branding outreach through LinkedIn and other social media, industry trade shows, and virtual or remote in-person presentations, with and without SMEs.

- Composed master contracts, statements of work (SOW), business rules documents, and responded to requests for Proposals/Information (RFP/RFI) applying comprehensive knowledge of business protocols and norms
- Participated in annual budget and business planning and contributed department information
- Left to pursue new opportunities after Guidemark Health acquired Tricore and converted business model from training agency to advertising and promotional media agency.

Business Development Manager

2005-2013

Joslin Diabetes Center, Boston, MA

- Oversaw non-philanthropic revenue development with focus on continuing medical education (CME) sales
- Grew average CME project value to \$450,000. Acquired industry-leading new accounts such as Abbott Labs, Merck, Solvay, Daiichi-Sankyo, and Boehringer-Ingelheim due to effective sales strategies, product and market knowledge, and acumen for relationship management.
- Increased annual sales from \$3 million to \$8 million within 3 years of hire due to identifying profitable new business growth opportunities in hypertension, obesity, and dyslipidemia markets
- Garnered national recognition for Joslin via development and delivery of 2 non-accredited programs, Nutrition IQ sponsored by SuperValu Supermarkets, and Healthseeker Facebook game sponsored by Boehringer-Ingelheim
- Launched 5 new-revenue streams: non-accredited professional education and speaker programs; training and performance improvement programs; disease state education, wellness and behavior modification patient education; and exhibit sponsorships at joint Joslin/Cleveland Clinic programs
- Increased pharmaceutical and device sales training revenue to over \$6 million in 7 years and generated over \$5 million in new revenue for non-accredited education sales over 5 years

Vice President, Advertising Sales

1994-2005

Miller Freeman Publishing (formerly Flatiron Publishing), New York, NY

- Awarded company's highest sales honor for 7 consecutive years (1997 to 2005) as top sales producer out of 350 sales professionals
- Started as regional sales manager and promoted to vice president of advertising sales
- Increased annual revenue from less than \$1 million to over \$3 million in first 3 years by successfully pursuing sizable new business accounts such as Microsoft, Hewlett Packard, SUN Microsystems, and Apple
- Developed international sales from under 0% to over 12% of total territory sales.
- Launched new publications in healthcare, telecommunications, IT, retail financial industry that achieved monthly sales quotas.

Education:

Master of Science in Health Administration with Informatics concentration Saint Joseph's University, Philadelphia, PA 3.89GPA

Bachelor of Arts in Liberal Arts Studies

Stonehill College, North Easton, MA

Certificates:

Certified Professional in Healthcare Information Management and Systems (CPHIMS)

Professional Affiliations:

Healthcare Finance Management Association (HFMA)

Healthcare Information Management Systems Society (HIMSS, NJHIMSS)

Healthcare Information Management Association (AHIMA)